Allen Firth

Full-Stack Developer | Architect

C# | Asp.Net | SignalR

Angular | React | TypeScript

ComosDB | Sql Server

Azure Platform Technologies,

Azure DevOps

Git | GitHub

Qualifications

BCom (Informatics) 2004 University of South Africa

Over 22 years of industry experience developing and architecting software solutions.

Info / Contact

+27 (0)60 840 7793

allen@codestream.co.za

Please see my personal and company websites for more details on my skills and experience.

www.codestream.co.za

www.allenfirth.info

Online Profiles

LinkedIn

GitHub

Profile

As a full stack developer, I specialize in working with **Angular / React**, **C#**, **Asp.NET Core**, **SQL Server / CosmosDB** and **Azure Platform Technologies**.

With more than <u>22 years</u> of industry experience, I have led development teams and developed software solutions for large corporations and small startups.

My expertise lies in building and designing complex systems using industry best practice. I believe in incorporating automated testing into the development life cycle and using continuous integration in conjunction with continuous deployment where relevant.

Over the course of my career, I have worked with a diverse range of industries and sectors, and have been involved in all aspects of the software development lifecycle - from project conception and analysis, to design, implementation, deployment, and ongoing maintenance and support of the final product.

Experience

Jul 2022 - Current - Uniper Energy (Germany, Fully Remote)

I was team lead and full-stack developer on a project aimed at creating a system to handle the inputs necessary for operating their Power Price Agreement valuation models related to renewable energies. This system also involved visualizing and analysing the timeseries outputs generated by these models.

Our team was assigned the responsibility of re-writing the system as the prior version of the application was unable to meet the business requirements. Our team successfully accomplished the mandate and made significant improvements in the performance of the key functional areas of the application, enhancing performance by an order of magnitude.

[Angular, Ngrx, SignalR, C#, Asp.NET Core, Azure CosmosDb, Azure platform technologies]

Jan 2022 - Jul 2022 - Clifford Chance (London, Fully remote)

I was requested to offer technical and architectural guidance and input to an existing team of developers. Our primary objective was to upgrade the technology of an existing <u>Partner system</u> that was utilized for managing global partner remuneration in various tax regions. As a team, we improved the performance of the application while also incorporating industry best practices to enhance the code quality and design. [Angular, C#, Azure Sql Server]

Jul 2021 - Dec 2021 - Anglo American (London, Fully Remote)

As a full stack developer, I contributed to a project that involved building an **Exposure reporting tool**. The tool utilized SignalR to showcase live intraday trades and exposure movements. The complexity of the project lay in managing large working datasets that contained multiple reporting dimensions, and handling regularly changing data in response to daily trades. [Angular, AG Grid, SignalR, C#, Asp.NET Core, Azure Synapse, Azure platform technologies]

2017 – 2021 Various contracting / consulting roles:

I built the <u>Vendor master data management</u> system for <u>The SPAR Group</u> using <u>Angular</u> and <u>C# APIs</u>. I was instrumental in development of SPAR's central <u>DataLake reporting database</u> (using **SQL Server**) which I later migrated to the **Azure Cloud** using **Azure Data Factory** and **Azure Synapse**.

I've worked **remotely** on a live data processing system for <u>Chelsea Football Club</u> in the **UK**, receiving, analysing, and processing player GPS, acceleration and speed data being fed live into an **Azure** processing pipeline using **Azure EventHub**, **Azure Functions** and **Azure Sql Server**.

I've worked remotely for CashRewards in Australia building their new Customer Coupon Management site using Angular.

I've worked **remotely** for **PROFiltr** in the **UK** bringing their online solution for small bookkeeping companies to completion using **AngularJS**, **NodeJS** and **MongoDB**

2014 - 2017, SMEasy (CTO, Architect and Developer)

I was CTO for a small FinTech start-up operating out of <u>Durban, South Africa</u>. SMEasy provided an easy-to-use online accounting package for small to medium enterprises.

I was instrumental in redirecting the architecture and technology choices of the product as well as leading and directing a near rewrite of the system using modern frameworks and introducing cutting edge development practises to the development team. SMEasy was developed using **Angular**, **C#**, **Asp.Net** and **Azure SQL Server** and **Azure DevOps**.

2008 – 2014, London, Various contracts

I spent six and a half years plying my trade as a sought-after software developer in **London**. I gained experience working with top talent in large corporate environments such as <u>Man Investments</u>, <u>BritInsurance</u> and <u>Freshfields Bruckhaus Deringer</u>. I spent the last three years in London working for <u>Digiterre</u> on various projects for the likes of <u>EDF</u> and <u>M&G Asset Management</u>.

A more detailed account of my working history can be obtained on request.